jobsagar.com 2016-05-11

# Jobsagar.com - Privacy Policy

| 

At **Jobsagar.com** , we take your privacy seriously! Please read this **Statement of Privacy** to be more aware about our policy on collecting, using and disclosing personal information. This website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. 

**Scope of coverage**  
This Statement of Privacy covers how Jobsagar.com treats personal information collected and received, including information relating to the past use of our products and services. "Personal Information" refers to information that personally identifies you by your name, email address or phone number and other information that is not otherwise available publicly. This Statement of Privacy applies only to the practices of Jobsagar.com and the people we employ or manage. Other websites or services linked to/from this website will have their own statements of privacy which can be viewed by clicking on their respective privacy links. 

**Collection of your Personal Information**  
 **Jobsagar.com** collects personal information, such as your name, email address, home or work address or telephone number, work experience and other such data associated with a resume for job applications. When you register with **Jobsagar.com** and sign in to our services, you are no longer unknown to us. 

**Jobsagar.com** keeps track of your transactions with us and some of our affiliated business partners, including information about your use of the products and services offered. 

**Jobsagar.com** also keeps track of the pages our users visit within **Jobsagar.com** , for business and security purposes. We may use this data to deliver customized content and advertising to users whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area. 

**Jobsagar.com** uses the collected information for the following general purposes: customizing the advertisement and content you see, fulfilling your requests for products and services, improving our services, contacting you, enforcing our Term of Use Policy, conducting research and providing relevant reports for our internal and external clients. 

**Jobsagar.com** may collect information about your computer hardware and software. This information includes your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. We use this information for operating our services, maintaining the quality of the service, security management and providing reports for relevant business purposes. 

**Jobsagar.com** uses candidate and section to provide registration and sign-in services. All the registration information you provide is stored by us in your candidate profile. For more information about a candidate account, please visit: http://jobs.jobsagar.com  
Please keep in mind that when you apply for jobs advertised on **Jobsagar.com** , your resume data in your candidate account and any other information that you disclosed during your job application will be made available to the companies you are applying to. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to browse that are linked from **Jobsagar.com** so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. We are not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on such websites outside the **Jobsagar.com** domain name. 

**Use of your Personal Information**  
 **Jobsagar.com** does not sell, rent or share your personal information with other people or non-affiliated third parties except to provide you with the products or services you have requested. When you give us permission, or under these circumstances: 

  * When you apply to jobs through our services, your resume data in your account and any other information that you disclosed during your job applications will be made available to the companies you are applying to. 
  * We encourage you to evaluate interview requests carefully and only confirm those you want to attend. Employers have the right to access any record of no-show or late cancellations to confirmed interview appointments. 
  * Besides that, you may also opt for making your resume searchable by companies who use the **Jobsagar.com** "Searchable Resume Database" to recruit. The companies may retain a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. Though we endeavor to ensure that the companies comply with the relevant privacy laws, **Jobsagar.com** is not responsible for the retention, use or privacy of resumes by them or by any third party that could be related to or associated with these companies. 
  * **Jobsagar.com** works with business partners to provide some services. We provide the information only to trusted business partners who work with us or on our behalf under confidentiality agreements. Our business partners may use your personal information to help us communicate with you about offers from them or **Jobsagar.com**. However, our business partners do not have any independent right to share this information; 
  * **Jobsagar.com** observes the process of law and will establish or exercise our legal rights or defend ourselves against legal claims; 
  * **Jobsagar.com** believes in sharing information in order to investigate, prevent or act on illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of **Jobsagar.com's** Terms of Use, or as otherwise required by the law; 
  * Personal information collected on this site may be stored and processed in any country in which **Jobsagar.com** or its business partners, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.  

---  
  
 **Control of your Personal Information**  
 **Jobsagar.com** offers you various choices for the use and sharing of your personal information, as well as subscription to various marketing preferences, products or services. You may go to the candidate account page to edit your personal information and preferences at any time. You may choose not to receive any marketing material from **Jobsagar.com** or from any of our affiliated partners. You may also subscribe to additional products or services from this account. 

In addition, you may visit candidate section

 __

to view, edit or delete your personal information or discontinue your subscription to marketing preferences, products or services from the **Jobsagar.com** database. 

In both cases described above, you will be asked to make your requests while logged into a candidate account, so that **Jobsagar.com** can associate your preferences with a particular service. This security safeguard prevents someone else from making choices about the usage and control of your personal information. 

You may also stop the delivery of future promotional emails from **Jobsagar.com** by following the specific instructions in the emails you receive or in the candidate account page. The instructions explain how to stop receiving such e-mails.   
However, there are some **Jobsagar.com** services that send out periodic emails to inform you of technical service issues, product surveys, new feature announcements and news about our products and services. You will be unable to unsubscribe from these emails as they are considered an integral part of the service you have chosen. 

**Opt Out** You can delete your candidate account at any time in which event we will remove all access to your account and resume in the database. However, the resume will remain archived but not be accessible by anyone through the Internet. The deletion of your account does not affect resumes that you had already sent to employers. 

In the event **Jobsagar.com** goes through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified by email of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information and can choose to opt out from the database. 

**Security of your Personal Information**  
 **Jobsagar.com** is committed to protect the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, your personal information is stored on computer systems that are located in controlled facilities. When **Jobsagar.com** transmits highly confidential information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

**Use of Cookies**  
 **Jobsagar.com** uses cookies to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a webpage server. Cookies are assigned to and can identify you uniquely; a cookie can only be read by a web server that issued you the cookie. 

Cookies cannot run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Their primary use is to provide a convenience by saving you time. For example, if you personalize our pages or register with our services, a cookie will help **Jobsagar.com** to remember you on your subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, and so on. When you next return to **Jobsagar.com** , the information you previously provided is retrieved so you can easily use our features that you had customized. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers will accept cookies automatically, but you can usually set your browser to decline cookies. However, if you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to experience the full interactive features of **Jobsagar.com's** services or other websites you visit. 

**Jobsagar.com** links the information we store in cookies to personally identifiable information you submitted so that we can customize your experience on the Jobsagar.com site. 

**Use of Clear Gifs**  
Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information. We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. 

**Email to Friend**  
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about a job or our site, **Jobsagar.com** will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. A one-time email inviting your friend to visit the site will be sent to him/her automatically. **Jobsagar.com** stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral programme. 

**Resume References**  
If you choose to add references to your resume, **Jobsagar.com** will ask you for their names, telephone numbers, emails and position titles. This information will be enclosed as part of your job application and employers may contact them to get references for your applications. 

**Service Providers**  
 **Jobsagar.com** may use third parties to provide 1) payment gateway services for optional services, 2) a profiling/assessment service, 3) serving of online advertisements and 4) web analytics on our website. When you sign up for such services or by using our website, they may collect some information (e.g., credit card numbers, name) as necessary for the third party to provide that service. 

**Third-Party Tracking Technologies**  
Jobsagar.com uses the Google Analytics tracking technology to track visits to our site. It allows us to analyze the usage of our site and is merely for our internal use. We do not tie information in Google Analytics to your personally identifiable information.

 **Articles**  
 **Jobsagar.com** will ask your permission to post your testimonial or success story. If you agree to post your material on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit can be read, collected, or used by other users of this site and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. **Jobsagar.com** will not be responsible for the personally identifiable information you may choose to submit in these testimonials/ success stories. 

**Exercising Your Choices As Jobsagar.com Users**  
During the candidate account registration process, you are given the choice to subscribe to the **Jobsagar.com** Dream Weavers, you may also given the choice to subscribe to a **Jobsagar.com** mailers or sms (if any), subscribe or purchase new products and services, subscribe to third-party mailers and receive offers from **Jobsagar.com** sent on behalf of our affiliated business partners. 

If you have made your choice to receive or purchase any or all of the above mentioned, you may remove yourself and your personal information from the recipient’s list at any time by logging into your account through 

_www.jobsagar.com_

, and then make the necessary changes at the "Account Info" section of the webpage. 

**Critical Performance Errors**  
You may occasionally see a message informing you of a critical performance error in **Jobsagar.com**. This message will ask you to send data to **Jobsagar.com**. If you agree, our technical support team or user care team will use the data to help determine what caused the error. 

Before you choose to send your data to **Jobsagar.com** , you have the opportunity to review that data. If you choose to send the data, in some cases your personal information may also be sent together. However, this personal information is deleted before we review the error data you send. 

**Terms of Forums**  
To guide you in using HR zone responsibly, Jobsagar.com has established the following rules. If you do not abide by these rules while using HR zone, Jobsagar.com has the right to prohibit you from using HR zone and may terminate your account that you may have on it. We do insist that you abide by the rules and policies detailed below that while using HR zone we may not: ** __**

  * upload, post, email, transmit or otherwise distribute any data, text, information, messages, software, music, sound, photographs, graphics, video messages or other material:
  * constituting or encouraging conduct that would intentionally or unintentionally violate any applicable local, state, provincial, national or international law or give rise to civil liability, or otherwise use HR zone in a manner which is contrary to law;
  * that is harmful, threatening, abusive, harassing, tortious, defamatory, vulgar, obscene, libelous, invasive of another's privacy, hateful or racially, ethically or otherwise objectionable;
  * that you do not have a right to transmit under any law or under any other arrangement, contractual or otherwise;
  * that is protected by patent, trademark, trade secret, copyright or other similar intellectual property right of any person without obtaining the permission of the holder of such intellectual property right; or
  *  upload, post, email, transmit or otherwise distribute any unsolicited or unauthorized advertising, promotional materials, "junk mail", "spam", "chain letters", "pyramid schemes", or any other form of solicitation except where specifically permitted on Jobsagar.com
  *  impersonate any person or entity or falsely state or otherwise misrepresent your affiliation with any person or entity; or
  * Collect or store personal data about other users of Jobsagar.com.

Doing any of these, will get you banned from our site without warning. 

Jobsagar.com enables its users to post content (i.e.; articles, reviews, blogs, etc.) and comments on content, products and services (herein known as "HR Chronicle"). Such users are solely responsible for any and all information posted as well as any consequences that may result from "HR Chronicle". In posting your material, you are agreeing that you are the sole creator of that content and you are the owner of that copyrightJobsagar.com is not liable for any damages arising from the use of "HR Chronicle". We have the right to refuse and remove any content uploaded, posted, emailed in the HR zone including "HR Chronicle". 

**Changes to this Statement**  
 **Jobsagar.com** will occasionally update this **Statement of Privacy** to reflect company and user feedback. When we post changes to this Statement, you will see the word "updated" next to the **Privacy Statement** link on the front page of **Jobsagar.com**. If there are material changes to this Statement or in the manner **Jobsagar.com** will use your personal information, we shall post a prominent notice on the Web site 30 calendar days prior to implementing the change. 

**Jobsagar.com** encourages you to review this Statement periodically to be informed of how we are protecting your personal information.  
  
|  |
